[Music]
[Applause]
we've been waiting like two years to do
the fifth round but to be honest it's
not that exciting
she became a part-time per day darling
she and day can be sunny a shindig
changeup
it
[Music]
Tom gave tone ah time to do casserlyjim
passenger
[Music]
okay
absolutely
[Music]
in character
blow your nose I didn't get a nice feed
corn again all that turn your phone off
is Michael
and then come to the small noises in the
room
desire room
rest your mind on those noises like
resting your head on a pillow
then please come to your heartbeat
first formula it's not really the first
formal meditation that would be deeper
but it's a good start
now come inside the heart to a beautiful
meditation room filled with sunlight in
the walls at the heart are beating
around you
more quiet place
and now go deeper to the core of the
heart the inner room still full of
sunlight but the beating walls seem far
away
walk quiet
now imagine a single crystal of sugar on
your finger and place your mind inside
try to focus like a laser like a tip of
a needle try to keep your concentration
in that one spot still the room is
sunlit and spacious and comfortable but
it at the same time it's like the tip of
an a needle
very single point
now flex your meditation muscle show
that you can inside the sugar crystal
you can imagine vast ocean as big as
this planet very deep if you like you
can go to the center and drop a single
drop of water in the middle of the ocean
and watch the ripples go out to the
endless sides of the ocean raspado
pick up piece of the ripple and follow
it as it goes to the edge which is not
there edgeless
and add the lifeless sky above the dark
devotion stretch your mind up infinitely
to space while you still keep the ocean
in mind but you're focused on the sky
then that's third formless realm
Louisville turn them my dog try to stop
our thoughts relax have fun into
complete quiet in the mind relaxing
quiet in the mind if a thought comes up
then wrestle we didn't stop it so part
of your mind is vigilant
shishun watching the mind for thoughts
and main mind is quiet
now keep the mind turned off but let the
thoughts just float around outside of
the core go to the core of the mine
turn turn dog and random thoughts and
feelings just move around the outside of
the mind
now think of one of the teachers are in
your life it may be a different one than
the last few days and with a faction
which i think is the kind of respect ask
them to come sit with you help you with
a meditation could be father mother
could be school teachers could be the
person who taught you your job that you
do could be a spiritual teacher could be
a historical teacher like Buddha or
Jesus or mom
now think of some quality that you
really admire about this teacher
something about this teacher that you
really admire you have a great love for
this quality you would like to have this
quality they're their best quality their
favorite quality
now have fun got your past line be a
innovator like the guards in our Sangha
have fun find a new story be creative
keep it going don't just go to some
century in some country some body and
then stop and wait for me to go on make
the story more and more beautiful
more and more detail about what did you
do in your past time to create this
beautiful quality
it's just imagination maybe someday
we'll see it directly but where do you
see it directly or whether you imagine
it it's coming from the same seeds so in
that sense anything you can imagine
it's it's part a wheel so start with
imagination and it will plant the seeds
later to see these past lives directly
what did you do in your past life that
was similar to what you see because that
must have caused what you see in your
teacher
then please come back to the teacher and
feel a new appreciation for that quality
oh when that quality came from me so
we're looking at the same teacher as we
were looking at before but now we feel
differently about the quality and we
kind of rejoice coffee meditation done I
was able to create such a a person I was
able to create this quality this quality
came from my goodness and I can keep
this quality in my life if I just keep
doing those good things I can keep this
teacher in this quality and guiding me
in my life like a message from my pastor
from myself to myself
all the qualities that can think of that
I see in people around me all the good
qualities that I ever saw in my life in
other people are coming from me
three eight deep exhales push out the
extra bath at the end and tell your
stomach tightens
and then slowly open your eyes take a
stretch drink something
[Music]
any questions
comments
thank you for teaching geshe-la I have a
question from yesterday's teaching and I
don't have my notes in front of me and I
apologize that I'm not understanding it
so I hope I phrased us correctly but I
get that the tree doesn't come from the
seed and the way that we think we it
does but you said that Nagarjuna said
that if a thing doesn't overlap in time
with its cause then it's not actually
connected so if the seed and the tree
don't exist in the same moment of time
then they're not dependent upon each
other so if I take that same analogy to
a karmic seed and then how could the
karmic seed cause the karmic result
yeah good question
I keep hoping people won't think of this
question I think you have to apply it's
it's kind of the question about the
emptiness of emptiness you see like do
the rules that apply to seeds and trees
do they also apply to karma and its
consequences right and there's a whole
chapter he's gonna talk about it but in
the same way that lets you think about
the pen and the writing right and the
microphone and the Sun coming up so it's
easy to see that
banging on the microphone doesn't cause
the Sun to come out that's like a false
cause and effect and and mankind
humankind has had many of those in its
history probably we're doing some of
those well everything is that some kind
of very foolish idea that is it's almost
like a superstition or recall primitive
superstition you can see tribes of
people banging on drums to make the Sun
come up the next day you know and then
in modern times were more sophisticated
and but are we you know do things really
happen the way we think they do does a
pen cause the writing and the god-honest
what the Guardian is trying to say is no
the pen doesn't cost the writing first
your mind creates a pen and then your
mind creates writing and your mind links
them together your mind creates that
connection so it in normal thinking of
our world world of pain right Wheel of
Life
samsara we feel like the pen is creating
the writing and we strongly feel that
then we hear someone saying oh you know
that's not how you write a book by
getting some good pens you help someone
else write a book right and that's what
causes the writing so can we apply the
same thing to the seeds which created
the writing and the seeds which created
the pen can we say the same thing that
somehow when we think about Karma
opening karmic seed opening and creating
something that we're doing the same
thing again we're thinking the same way
again
about karma seeds that we think about
pens and writing maybe we're making the
same mistake about it we think that the
writing comes from or the book came from
helping someone else write a book but I
think somehow the point is that we're
making the same mistake again when we
think about how karma causes something
so it's tempting to think that by
definition karmic seed is creating the
book or karmic students creating the pen
but maybe it's not like that you know
maybe maybe that connection itself is
coming from different seeds you see it I
mean maybe our understanding of it is
maybe we're carrying the same bad habit
of how cause-and-effect happens to to
when geshe-la explains how everything's
really coming from your seeds right so I
think the answer is there I think the
answer is there somewhere I think and
and we're gonna discuss it today in
class the whole class but we have a
strong desire you know that old desire
to think that and by the way that's the
real meaning of desire the old desire to
think that the pen causes the writing
that there's something independent that
could cause the writing is when we learn
about the gardener then we say oh now I
understand it's really my mental thing
cause the writing really
we're doing it we just change our object
of desire to the mental state from the
pen you see I mean and and Buddha said
that's the real meaning of desire
that's why Buddha kept repeating don't
have desire it doesn't secondary desire
for for money or sex or whatever
these are come from the deeper desire
which is to think that money comes from
competing or that sex comes from bad
behavior I mean it's a deeper desire so
what I mean is I think what we're doing
is when I explained about the pen and
the writing and I explained that instead
of going like this it goes like this you
know then you want to do the same then
you decide oh then the real seed is my
mental state in comic scene but then
you're just moving that misperception
misunderstanding to this
misunderstanding you see you see I mean
other the mental seed has the real power
inside of it and that's not coming from
me you just move your misunderstanding
to another level you know I think that's
the answer I think that's the answer
sorry I forgot to mention the second
quick question Hey
okay so so if Nagarjuna says that in
order for two things to be connected
they have to exist at the same time
could you just give an example of two
things that are connected that exist at
the same time I can't
we're gonna study it today it's by the
way here he attacks the four kinds of
conditions he calls them conditions
right why does he call them conditions
and not causes because the first one is
called the cause conditions so he
attacks them together and then he's
gonna attack them one by one
he's gonna attack their definition one
by one and then at the end he comes back
and attacks them together again so first
he attacks them together the concept of
a cause he attacks and then he attacks
the four of them one by one and then at
the end of the chapter by the way we're
almost to the end of the chapter the
chapters are small which is very
nagarjuna we're going to go back to
proving light causes can't work anyway
and where he's gonna go I think tomorrow
is by the way Tim I'm not quite done
with tomorrow as you noticed and I have
a board meeting today so it's gonna be
all night for the translators but the
final word he's going to say is look
this thing about the cause and result
having to touch that cause and result
having to over them who who caused the
trouble in the first place was Lord
Buddha you know who said that in the
first place
it was Lord Buddha he blames it all on
Lord Buddha and by the way part of your
mind is wandering probably I guess so
where was the middle way school during
Lord Buddha's time you know if if middle
waist is the ultimate answer then why
did it take seven hundred years for
someone to talk about it you know
didn't boot up found the middleweight
school this whole chapter is there a
basis in the Buddhist teaching can you
point to a specific teaching where
Buddha taught the first chapter the
content of the first chapter so we're
gonna go on that tomorrow but here's the
punchline Buddha said his big big thing
was if this happens that will happen you
know and that's
he didn't say dependence he didn't say
dependent origination
he just said over and over again
teaching arena teach od2 Maya teaching
and there's sutras called if this
happens that happens but somehow they
have to touch if they don't touch then
this happened this create that and then
and then and then and then because they
create everything it doesn't touch so
either they exist at the same time for a
little while at the end of the first
thing and at the beginning of the second
thing or else random you know if they
don't have to touch if the hand doesn't
have to touch the writing at any point
then then pens can make fish and pigs
and you know because they also else are
not connected to pen you can either
they're connected and they're not
connected if there's some connection
then pens are connected to writing if
there's no connection then pens can
create peace because if it can create
one thing that it's not connected to
it'll create a million things there's
not connected what's the difference why
should it create writing if it's not
connected to it got it then it should
create anything where's the theme they
have to touch the similarity first law
of karma right there has to be some
similarly if they don't connect then
there doesn't have to be similarly if
they do connect there has to be
similarly
okay that's how Buddha would answer and
we're gonna go to a Sutra tomorrow
there are sutras from which you know you
should be wondering where did in the
garden to get his stuff you know what
what Sutra didn't Gardner talk from and
we're gonna go there tomorrow but I'm
still writing it okay let's do matter
taking questions and then we'll do
philosophy questions in the class
because you'll get tired there's the one
behind you Joe Thank You Angela and when
we're doing the emptiness meditation of
the Lama then we go and imagine the past
life and some sort of good seed we
planted but you say in emptiness
meditation and but it's actually a
dependence a karma meditation because
you're not picturing as a negative and
negative an absence and absence of a of
a self existent thing and and then their
own look very different the self
existent Lama from the projected Lama
you mention what the feeling can you
please explain what how can we know when
we have a feeling that something's or
projection and how can we know when we
have a feeling that something is not a
projection it's self existent and
especially because you what this is
supposed to make you see emptiness
directly so you gotta recognize the
feeling of what a self existent mind is
me and my mind
and what I projected me and my mind is
which is this is where you're taking us
but it's more about feeling right not
instances of time or parts or is it can
you please explain yeah okay yeah so the
whole lines dance in my trail by my
trail when he mentioned it he he's
saying it's connected to the wheel of
life and it's the source for the wheel
of life teaching dependence the twelve
links in in Scripture and the source for
the Lions death are the same verse okay
Danis thinking and competing in turn on
your ship a tangent Elgin looted on the
meeting the DA purge a very famous so
the first two lines are one line in
Sanskrit is lions dance and then second
line is about dependent origination
but there's amazingly in one verse the
third and fourth line are about depend
dependence and the fourth law is about
emptiness so when he teaches the wheel
of life in two lines and the lions dance
the first two lines and then Wheel of
Life in the third and fourth line the
third line is about basically it's about
dependence and the fourth lines about
emptiness because he says Luke meetin
means spin the wheel back you know spin
the wheel back break the wheel out the
first link you know stop thinking that
the pen created the writing who make
movies yeah if you don't like a movie
whose father then you know it's really
funny to me I mean ever since I became a
Buddhist life is kind of strange because
people will say I'm so pissed off this
used to be a good director you know but
this last movie is terrible you know
they're like yeah but
and he said yeah but you don't know
guess mine he used to make good movies
and now the moment you know such a bad
ending you know and then I'm like I
can't have conversations with people
because I'm like I can't say what I
really think I have to say yeah you're
right you know it's really bad he's
getting older and he's probably can't
make movies you know but really you make
the next part of the movie right the
movies coming out of here when you turn
the page of a book it's blank there's
nothing there then your mind writes the
next page in a in 165th of a second your
mind lays down the words if you don't
like the ending of the movie you know
make better relapse by the way I heard
some real nuts last night and they were
really awesome and I'm gonna try to
adjust the schedule Tim to give more
time to I would like to hear more
relapse from people we could have spent
all night last night just listening to
people's from your lives I heard two
cool dudes impossible connection yeah
but there was another one all does
what's yours Oh yours this right I mean
what was your is with you are the mirror
enjoy the mirror yeah okay anyway so
you're absolutely right the part where
you think about your past now we are
studying dependence we're not focusing
on emptiness yeah so when you look at
your teacher and you think of this
called it came from something I did
that's dependent tangent dull June look
tune okay that part of the quotation and
then
then we have to take a break because I
don't want to make everybody there has
to be a pee-pee break between dependence
and emptiness
no because emptiness takes more focus
seriously when you leave the lion's den
to remember don't go straight to
emptiness and then peepee because people
are concentrating okay so after the
dependence we come back and we focus on
the emptiness of the of the Nama now
what's the feeling
what's the difference in the feeling the
famous story I tell is I was sitting in
my Lamaze classes for 25 years you know
and I know I think I told you story
probably I did because I told every
story but anyway we have these folding
chairs and they were wooden
maybe somebody remembers them maybe
that's what messed up your head I don't
know they were really hard and they were
built wrong and they were soup the mint
within two minutes you feel
uncomfortable after two hours and you
feel like torture you know and he taught
in the Tibetan way which is how I used
to teach before this week we just just
talk at you and you don't have to do
homework you don't have to do anything
he's just talking you for two hours
three hours and no PP breaks and you're
supposed to listen like this if if you
look down or something if your hands not
moving he said what why you're not
taking notes and so you're like this
sometimes you just write anything
you're not supposed to ask question but
you know he went on and on and on about
this feeling you know it's a feeling and
then finally I I couldn't stop myself I
remember two or three famous times I
couldn't stop my stuff I said look I
raised my hand you know he's like what
then I'm like I I see the door you know
because I was thinking about he is to
give us tea and snacks after the class
so I keep looking at the door you know
and then I said I'm looking at the door
right now and according to high school a
middle way I'm doing something wrong all
the time
there is no Sam ultimately speaking
there's no tumor
there's no correct perceptions not that
you never have until you see emptiness
directly an accurate perception of
anything ever in your whole life and
then I'm like so what am I doing wrong
when pétain it's there at door there
isn't there a door there what I really
meant was isn't there tea on the other
side what's the mistake I'm making he
said you're not making a mistake about
the door so get that clear when you look
at the door and you identify it as a
door that's not a mistake that's a what
we call an accurate perception pomona
that's correct
you see a door that part's not mistaken
but you have a feeling about the door I
thought what's the feeling about the
door you know and he said you know you
think that it didn't come from you you
feel like that strongly you think it
didn't come from your past life it
didn't come from what you did yesterday
you know maybe how my friends talked to
me or how my wife behaves comes from me
that
I understand but door you know door
comes from door factory you know didn't
come from me then there's that's the
feeling wrong feeling about the door and
there's a joke that when you teach the
pen there's an old joke which by the way
in ancient times was a conch shell a
white show you didn't use a pan you use
the shell and there's a joke that while
you're explaining to someone how it
comes from them they feel like it comes
from the pen while you're explaining it
they also are miss feeling it got it
even while you're explaining it that it
doesn't come from it so they they're
like looking at it and they're feeling
that it comes from itself and they're
going I get it I get it come from me but
the feeling is the billions of years
have it it's so very difficult so we're
gonna go to the feeling next and we'll
go to the emptiness meditation next
which is after the pp bank so have a
good break remember to look stop and
look at the bathroom door for a while
what am I doing wrong
but don't think too long
[Music]
okay let's go we can get back in by
watching 10 breaths okay so let's watch
10 breath breath begins with the exhale
now please bring back to the room the
teacher that you chose before do I see a
teacher yes do I have the right feeling
about where they come from usually not
so focus on that nice quality they have
and think about how it came from seeds
in your mind and those seeds are always
planted by being aware of ourselves so
karma is planted by being aware of
ourselves
I was I was kinder I was patient in my
past 9
I observed myself being kind of patient
maybe consciously maybe not consciously
but that observation of myself planted
those seeds so first enjoy how those
seeds are coming up we are opening and
creating this nice quality we seen one
of the feelings you can have at this
moment is kind of comfort that all this
teachers good qualities are actually
coming from me and that means if I am
smart then I can keep this teacher
because I can make more sense I make a
lot of good seeds to see that quality
just by being happy about it I make a
tremendous amount of good seeds by
understanding where it came from
so there's this sort of comfort that I I
can protect myself from losing this
teacher by planting more of those seeds
and that's the real meaning of taking
refuge in Buddhism
now ask that teacher please sit to the
side because I need to do an emptiness
meditation to do an emptiness meditation
there has to be something that I refuse
or deny there must be something I cancel
and that should be something that could
never exist you exist you're my teacher
you have this beautiful quality so
please sit to the side now I bring
another teacher that looks just like you
to sit in front of me but this teacher
is different they have patience or
kindness which is not coming from me
inside their mind inside of them from
their own effort and their own practice
they have developed the patience or
kindness maybe it took many years and
they have this quality inside of them
it's coming from inside of them and then
it comes out to the surface and I see it
in their actions and in what they say I
see this cutting this which is deep
inside of them it comes out sometimes
and they say a kind thing sorry they're
a patient so now think of your teacher
this way
that the patience is inside of them and
this is impossible this is what we call
true nature this is their nature this is
part of them and that's a wrong idea
that's a wrong idea even if they had
practiced patience for many years and
even if they feel patient all the time
but I don't have the seeds then I could
even see them as angry all the time
think about we call effect teacher
boo-boo Lama the one I didn't create and
try to understand how they don't exist
if they did exist you couldn't keep them
then we didn't come from your effort you
would lose them one day
[Music]
now let's start round two invite back
the real teacher the one who comes from
you appreciate that you created this
goodness and take your leave
bring start to come back down we'll go
first to the fourth formless realm never
turn off the mind coming out of the
center we are starting at the center of
the mind where we looked at our teachers
dependence and emptiness and now we are
coming back out to the normal world so
we start with the mind try this part
should be relaxing don't struggle
don't fight kind of enjoying coming out
slowly from your meditation the mind in
your mind with no thoughts if thoughts
come let them float away I think it's
good to do this other rounds a little
bit more quickly you are tired
meditating is difficult work for the
body and also very difficult for the
mind to focus the mind or control the
mind is is like fighting with the wild
horse and it's tiring you're sitting on
your cushion but it's actually quite a
lot of effort and it's tiring so come
back down smooth and happening
come out a little noisy replace third
formless realm level and you're watching
your different thoughts and trying to
slow them down deflect them from the
quiet of the mine
come out more smoothly into a blue sky
swabbie
to the ocean
into the sugar crystal single point
single needle point
come on a little more to the inner room
of the heart beating at a distance
lots of sunlight push out extra exhales
from time to time don't let prana build
up in the heart chakra
inside the heart while speeding
and then to the beating heart for room
number one double number one we stay
here we don't go out to the air
conditioner
let's go pack up
into the center of the heart into the
room at the heart
round 3
deeper to the middle of the heart
sugar crystal
relax you're tired
this is sticking in yoga this is when
you build up your strength so appreciate
that don't avoid it don't be afraid of
it stick with it this is the kind of
endurance and meditation you need if you
want to see emptiness directly and help
other people you learn
to the ocean wide
to the sky
even wider
try to rest try to relax in the pose
turn off your mind
block type
go to the core of that and stop
listening to the thoughts
greet your teacher remember where this
good quality came from
around 4:00 stick with it stay with it
relax don't find it come back to the
heartbeat so we jump from nine down to
one
in round four we're gonna go back to
ninth mama but on the way between each
number we're gonna bring the llama back
think about where they came from think
about their good quality think about how
they are not coming from inside of them
so you can have fun here make it
interesting focus on different things as
you do Belgaum velcome alternation
alternating between the form and
formless realm and the teacher so from
the heartbeat go back to the teacher
enjoying this nice quality now you see
that you wrote the book you've made the
movie I did a pretty cool job maybe I'm
not as bad as I thought it was
inside the heart that got a teacher
enjoy the quiet
back to the teacher try to remember what
you did before
in your MOOC imagine near in the past
life
into the inner chamber of the heart
heart beating at a distance
you can rest before we bring back the
teacher in the silent
bring back the teacher think some more
about what you did in your past life
maybe you have some new ideas about it
into the sugar crystal peace and quiet
one more detail about your past
to the ocean
relax during this eight levels relax the
mine rest of mine let it float on the
ocean
come back to your teacher I like to
insert in here how did I first meet them
and where I where I feel that came from
what's the wrong idea about how you met
them were you on a certain bus or plane
you're in a certain building and they
came into the building
you saw something on the Internet
and that's why you met them
to the sky
it's okay to speed up on fourth and
fifth round part of the exercise is
flexibility of the minor bring the llama
back why did you really meet them
turn the mind on
total quiet
then just happy that you created the
sense to see this number meet this
number
turn the mind off with no effort to stop
any thoughts let them float around go
deeper going to the sick
ah there's my llama became from me so
beautiful
so nice so well deserved and I'm gonna
keep them by continuing to be a good
person as well as I can
fifth round final round then we've done
the whole lion stands come back to the
mind with no thoughts no fighting
thoughts
now come to the air-conditioner and jump
out to the outside room from the 8th
level
jump out to the outside room show how
strong your mind is I can jump to an
outside sound purposely not because it
demanded my attention and I can slide
back right now in 10 no mind level 7
silence
I have control of my mind I can tell it
where to go this is meditation
jump out to the air-conditioner
let's go to the sky
jump out to the air-conditioner rest
your mind on the air-conditioner
and then rested on the ocean that's
judges beyond the horizon
and jump back to this room and these
noisy machines
and then watch I can jump into a sugar
crystal that will I have that authority
over my mind
jump out to the noisy machine
jump into the center of the heart jump
to the machine
jump to the inside of the heart beating
around me jump back to the machine
jump back into your body and watch your
heart
and then three long exhales push the
extra air out at the end so you don't
get tight
it's like shavasana
open your eyes take a stretch
congratulations you're the first group
to do the Viktor Bout like that all
right then if you want to come up and
turn off your phone you can do that
there's actually a little bit more
there's a dessert it's not round six but
you know there's a traditional way to
end the meditation which we'll practice
tomorrow okay
there's a one minute thing you have to
do any questions Wow
drink something okay Thank You Kara
regarding the sugar crystal single point
focus it's a bit hard how to balance
that because then I see the sugar
crystal here but as a and at the same
time your guide article to imagine
inside of it to be a special place so oh
yeah personally you know when I give DCI
talks then let's say I'm doing Wheel of
Life and Scott always has this laser
things and I ask God you know give me
the laser thing cuz I always lose it he
never he never lets me hold it he keeps
saying and then you know I use it and I
aim it at the picture and I pushed the
wrong button and he tells me again it's
not that button it's the other button
then then I push it and then there's
this spot of light comes okay so the eye
the feeling should be like that and I
promised you I would go through the
technical meditation thing today how
about tomorrow I'm having a lot of
trouble keeping up with your homeworks
okay so I'll do it tomorrow I'll try to
I need to look at it again but the
traditional scripture at this point
kdj he will talk about the sugar crystal
part is very big emphasis on single
points so you know see if you can work
it in the point is any time you're in
meditation it's useful to go to a small
place so if you are doing Tumlin
meditation or some you you're supposed
to see a rose in your heart or lotus in
your heart and there's a diamond in the
loaners then if you have trouble
focusing
there's a tradition to shrink it to a
tiny place in your heart to a single
point like the laser point and that's
tradition if you have trouble focusing
then shrink it to a tiny bit of your
heart there's another tradition to put
it here shrink it here and you might try
that sometimes when you want to increase
your focus and and that's trying to put
it inside a chakra so a lot of people
when they think about chakra and you say
oh the chakra it's called the mint um
which means between your eyebrows but
it's not it's a little higher okay but
there's no eyebrow here so they just say
between your eyebrow it means here you
know and it's here there's a chakra here
right in your chakra and the important
thing that they teach you in the
monastery is it's not painted on the
forehead it's not like in fact that's
why Indian women where I've been do
after they get married but it's to
represent a chakra which is actually
about a centimeter I don't know meters
very well half inch in so start on the
skin and then focus a little bit behind
that and you hit that bone and then
focus a little bit behind that until you
feel some concentration steel feel some
kind of something will click you know so
I think some people everybody's body is
different when they measure chakras they
measure them in chin this line because
that that's a Chinese medical way to
measure parts of your body as my teacher
taught me wait long ago
I did two years of two years I think
something in medicine with her but it
depends on your own body you see so
don't measure with a stick measure with
your own finger because some people's
fingers smaller because their body
smaller so that's going to be more
accurate
so one tune may be in and you might find
an opponent focus so if you have trouble
focusing its traditional you can call it
sugar crystal you can call it laser you
can call it h in your chakra command
center chakra but doesn't matter if you
go to a smaller point and it'll be
easier to focus okay if you get tight
if your chest gets tired or your back
starts to hurt a lot or you feel nervous
or something then ocean sky you know
open it up okay all right so somehow you
have to maintain this laser point even
though the crystal becomes as big as a
as a big apartment in conjure something
Shanghai okay sure sure your equipment
is hatching yeah yeah - sure Tatiana
Sedova come to her manager hall create
inside loss Italy collage the title Ajo
tool I mention the second constant to
meet attitude are sure home cut your
time we only reach out to her to let us
know particular society now mateo rubriz
hands out you go your institution
without you da hai on ie10 since the
lightener she - oh ho yotaka city - the
tools that I've had a so they go for me
a fee autonomy how to remember all this
it's okay
chinko ekun tak hai now holding
apartments in ha ha - yo pata cancer and
she shall hire sure
say ho - me too - oh ho just
yeah panicking whoa you who see the
thing super to like why would you leave
this home a house she went along suis
malade she show you went to show you
inside me holla she's here I'm gonna say
fast
yes so you said every time in our daily
life if we are busy we can finish the
the constants in the teacher in the in
level nine instead of the level eight
the previous eight but this time you ask
us to stop in the desire of the the the
noise after par 5 so it's it up we
stopped in the formula we didn't go to
the server we stopped that one we didn't
go to the ground floor
oh ok so we start here is it not fun
it's not good it's tradition because
when you see emptiness directly it's
from the first forum level so you it's
important it's a good seat to put in
your mind to stop there and yeah that's
re fine
round five no I'm thinking not to yeah
yeah oh I start the heart oh nothing
nice okay don't go to the air
conditioner it's you you will have to go
to the air conditioner or you can't go
to work but traditionally for good luck
because level one is where you see
emptiness from actually the level one
has three levels but we're not talking
about it but at the first of the three
novels Sundin demo near and oh me choked
me this level here you that's where you
see emptiness directly so
it's I'm thinking it's a good idea if we
stop there now that till then I say I'm
done with the meditation and then you
get up and you hear the another part of
her question is you you taught us to see
the seats opening and like the layer of
light like like a light coat put putting
on the teacher but you didn't do it this
time I feel like it's a pity good
question and then the last one is in the
final dedication new access to create
that with golden light to send our
legacies and we didn't didn't do it this
time
yeah also two ways to end the meditation
so when you teach it start with just
three breaths and then later connect
those breaths to dedication you see we
didn't do it yet we didn't treat you
maybe tomorrow
okay after they learned to dedicate with
the three breath then then teaching them
to bring the lama into their heart you
see so start with three breaths
get the student used to doing three
breaths and then suddenly saying okay
now use those three breaths to give away
the good karma and after they get used
to that then changing again because if
they learned everything you can't teach
anymore
just kidding then do that bring the Lama
into your heart but we're gonna do it
tomorrow how about a seat opening part
yeah now see the opening I think I
suggest you know there's too many things
to think about when you think about how
the seat opens how the picture comes out
how the picture coats mama like honey or
something you know or like a like a
sweater last night we needed a sweater
right
and you can I think a good place to do
that is in round four okay
because round four you just kind of in
between the aim you can have fun
Oh see the opening okay go back to the
heart
Oh code coming okay go back to the heart
oh you know you know you can have you
can do all those things there and
there's many many more you can do by the
end of five years you can do 27
different kinds of examinations during
the between the a-level
yeah good yeah round four round four
right
Pell gone with cocaine iam Jukes a bell
goes with coke pentium joke so that
means alternating meditation with a
cessation military but cessation means
you are meditating on emptiness so you
can call it an emptiness meditation
traditionally it's called cessation
meditation okay and then round five is
when you're coming down it's just do
come between the eight levels what's to
come yeah you call it in the sense get
something God - what's that Sutra called
bad Sutra
, yeah come out dot to come at that okay